{
    "id": "fce96ebcae3e49e5bf52dcbe2c6bdad5",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We started early in the morning so that we ……………………… not get stuck in the traffic.",
            "description": "Would, could and might are common after so that when the verb in the main clause is in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "may",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I had never before met so ………………………………",
            "description": "In this special structure we use so + adjective + a/an + singular countable noun.",
            "answers": [
                "a kind person",
                "kind person",
                "kind a person"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I was angry and so ……………………… the others.",
            "description": "The same auxiliary is used in both clauses in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "are",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He spoke in a low voice …………………………. avoid waking up the baby.",
            "description": "So as to means the same as in order to.",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "so as",
                "so as to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when they …………………………….",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They were watching TV when the burglars ………………………….. in",
            "description": "We use the simple past for the short action that took place in the middle of the longer action. ",
            "answers": [
                "break",
                "were breaking",
                "broke"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I usually drink coffee in the morning, but today I ……………………… tea.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to say that something happened on a particular occasion in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "drink",
                "drunk",
                "drank"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "James is one of the players who …………………………. been selected for the match.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the plural noun players hence we use have.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Each child ……………………………. given a prize.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She has been to ……………………………… all continents.",
            "description": "Almost means nearly. ",
            "answers": [
                "almost",
                "all most",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She would rather starve ……………………… beg.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… by the storm, we took shelter under a bridge.",
            "description": "We were driven by the storm. We took shelter under a bridge. We can combine these two clauses using the past participle driven.",
            "answers": [
                "Driving",
                "Drove",
                "Driven"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}